Guide to the Office of University Development records, 1947-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Office of University Development records 1947-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Office of University Development.
28.0 linear feet Extent: 14,300 Items
The Office of University Development is responsible for fund-raising programs in the areas of annual gifts, capital gifts, and program support. This collection contains printed promotional materials and annual reports as well as fund-raising materials such as mailings to alumni and parents. Additionally, there are VHS tapes and a DVD. There are a small number of photographs in this collection as well as questionnaires and gift records. The materials range in date 1947-ongoing.
uaunidev
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Some material is in off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Office of University Development records were received by the University Archives as transfers over a period of time.
Historical Note
The Office of University Development is responsible for fund-raising programs in the areas of annual gifts, capital gifts, and program support. The Gifts Records Office acknowledges all gifts to the University and maintains the official records on them, as well as the permanent files on all endowment funds. This office was formed in the Fall of 1971 by a merger of the gift record functions of the Alumni and Development Offices. The purpose of this merger was to centralize gift record functions. Development activities in the professional schools and in other areas of the University coordinate with and report to the Development Office.
Collection Overview
Contains materials created and distributed by the Office of University Development in the promotion of the University and its programs in fund-raising efforts. This collection includes printed promotional materials and annual reports as well as fund-raising materials such as mailings to alumni and parents. Additionally, there are VHS tapes and a DVD. There are a small number of photographs in this collection as well as questionnaires and gift records. The materials range in date 1947-ongoing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Office of University Development; Duke University. Alumni Association; Duke University. Alumni Association; Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Capital Campaign for the Arts and Sciences; Duke University. Department of Alumni Affairs; Duke University -- Endowments; Duke University -- Endowments -- Periodicals; Duke University -- Funds and Scholarships; Duke University -- Handbooks, Manuals, etc; Duke University. Office of Alumni Affairs; Duke University. School of Law -- Alumni and alumnae; Duke University. School of Medicine -- Alumni and alumnae; Duke University. Divinity School; Duke University. School of Forestry; Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences -- Funds and Scholarships
Related Material
Office of University Development Small Collections
Duke University Archives
Office of Institutional Advancement Records, 1958-1981
Duke University Archives
Alumni Affairs Records, 1851-2005
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Loyalty Fund Campaign, 1947-1977
  This series contains accessions A75-77 and A92-58.
  - The Loyalty Fund, 1948-1959 (Box 1)
  - The Duke University Loyalty Fund Campaign, 1947-1948
  - The Duke University Loyalty Fund Campaign, 1949-1950
  - Class Agents, 1948-1949
  - Class Agents, 1949-1950
  - November Letters, 1949-1950
  - Third Annual Report, 1949-1950
  - April Letters, 1949-1950
  - Area Campaign, 1949-1950
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1956-1957
  - Class Agents' Mailings and Reports, 1956-1957
  - Medical Agents' Mailings and Reports, 1956-1957
  - Medical Parents' Mailings, 1956-1957
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1957
  - Class Agents, 1957-1958
  - Fund Reports, 1957-1958
  - Class Agents' Mailings and Reports, 1957-1958
  - Undivided Classes, 1957-1958
  - Anniversary/Gift Programs, 1943-1958
  - Class Agents, 1953-1974
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1958-1959
  - Class Agents' Mailings, 1958-1959
  - Fund Reports, 1958-1959
  - Miscellaneous, 1958-1959
  - Class Agents' Mailings, 1959-1960
  - Fund Reports, 1959-1960
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960
  - Class Agents' Mailings, 1959-1960
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1960-1961
  - Class Agents' Mailings, 1960-1961
  - Fund Reports, 1960-1961
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961
  - Undergraduate Loyalty Fund Mailings, 1961-1962
  - Pace Setters List and Enclosures, 1961-1962
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1961-1962
  - Divinity School Mailings, 1961-1962
  - Law School Mailings, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Graduate School Mailings, 1961-1962
  - Forestry School Mailings, 1961-1962
  - Medical School Mailings, 1961-1962
  - Fund Reports, 1961-1962
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1961-1962
  - Class Agents' Mailings: All Schools and Colleges, 1961-1962
  - Giant Step Campaigns, 1961-1962
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962
  - Fund Report, 1961-1962
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1962-1963
  - Undergraduate Loyalty Fund Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Law School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Divinity School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Forestry School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Medical School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Graduate School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Loyalty Fund Progress Report, 1962-1963
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963
  - Pace Setters, 1962-1963
  - Undergraduate Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Law School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Divinity School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Forestry School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Graduate School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963
  - Progress Reports, 1962-1963
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1962-1963
  - Pace Setters, 1962-1963
  - Undergraduate Loyalty Fund Mailing, 1962-1963
  - Law School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Forestry School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Medical School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Graduate School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963
  - General Information for Class Agents, 1962-1963
  - Undergraduate Loyalty Fund Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Law School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Divinity School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Forestry School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Medical School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Graduate School Mailings, 1962-1963
  - Miscellaneous [papers from 1969-1970 intermingled here], 1962-1963
  - Loyalty Fund Progress Report, 1962-1963
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963
  - Divinity Class Agents, 1962-1964
  - Class Agents, 1964-1965
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Undergraduate 1942, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1942, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Undergraduate 1942, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1943, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1943, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1917, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1918, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Undergraduate 1957, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1957, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Law 1957, 1966-1967
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1920, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1921, 1969-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1945, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1945, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1945, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1922, 1969-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1946, 1969-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1946, 1969-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1946, 1969-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1947, 1971-1972
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1947, 1971-1972
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1947, 1971-1972
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Class of 1961, 1970-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1961, 1970-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1961, 1970-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Law 1961, 1970-1971
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Medical 1960, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Law 1960, 1969-1970
  - Anniversary Gift Programs: Divinity 1960, 1969-1970
  - Class Agents and Loyalty Fund, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Class Agents and Loyalty Fund, 1964-1965
  - Class Agents and Loyalty Fund, 1965-1966
  - Class Agents, 1966-1967
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1966-1967
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1967-1968
  - Class Agents and Mailings, Campaigns, 1968-1969
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1970-1971
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1971-1972
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1973-1974
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1974-1975
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1975-1976
  - Class Agents and Mailings, 1976-1977
- University Development Reunion Questionnaires, 1983-1987
  Series includes accession A93-80.
  - Class of 1928-Class of 1945 (Box 5)
  - Class of 1946-Class of 1959 (Box 6)
  - Class of 1959-Class of 1966 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1967-Class of 1973 (Box 8)
  - Class of 1974-Class of 1982 (Box 9)
- Capital Campaign, 1950-2004
  Series includes accessions A81-109, A92-113, A98-93, and A2005-0008.
  - Duke University Development Campaign Records, 1950-1959 (Box 10)
  - Clippings, 1984-1992
  - Mailings, 1985-1986
  - Fleishman, Joel: Outrageous Ambitions... A Report, 1985
  - Fleishman, Joel: Report to the Board of Trustees, 1988
  - Fleishman, Joel: Report to the Board of Trustees, 1989
  - Planning, 1988
  - The Duke Steuben Project, 1990
  - Susan B. King: Founder's Day, 1991
  - Mailing Lists, 1990 RESTRICTED
  - Campaign Kickoff Documents, 1998
  - Campaign Kickoff Photos, 1998
  - Trustees Resolution, 1995
  - Invitation/Packet, 1998
  - Symposium, 1998
  - Remarks by President Keohane at Campaign for Duke Meeting, 1998
  - VHS: Campaign for Duke Town Meeting, 1998
  - Campaign for Duke, 1998-2004 folders as follows:
    - Athletics
    - Bench Mark [newsletter]
    - Comprehensive Cancer Center
    - Campaign DVD and VHS
    - Divinity School
    - Duke Magazine
    - DUMC
    - School of Engineering
    - Fuqua
    - Identity Standards Model
    - School of Law
    - Libraries
    - Medical School
    - Nasher Museum of Art
    - NSOE
    - School of Nursing
    - Portrait
    - Trinity
    - University and Health System
    - Regional Campaign Councils Handbook
- Capital Campaign Printed Matter, 1965-2003
  Series includes accessions A75-177, A95-69, A92-113, A95-74, and materials with an unknown provenance.
  - Gift Planning, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Capital Gifts to Duke University, 1974-1980, 1982-1984
  - Overview: The Loyalty Fund Report, 1979-1982
  - Overview: The Duke University Annual Fund Report, 1982-1986
  - Duke Annual Fund Report and Special Reunion Tribute, Happy 40th Birthday, 1986-1987
  - Duke Annual Fund Report and Special Reunion Tribute, 1987-1988
  - Duke: To Cross a Threshold, circa 1980s
  - Pamphlets, 1971-1972
  - A Special Tribute: Class Reunion Gifts, 1981-1983
  - For the Future of Duke, undated
  - Gifts, Grants and Contracts to Duke University, 1980-1982
  - Duke Parents' Letter, 1983-1988
  - Planned Philanthropy... For the Future of Duke, 1973-1979, 1983, 1987, 1992
  - Quadrangle, 1984-1985, 1991
  - Guide for Volunteers, 1985
  - Outrageous Ambitions: Duke 2000 The Society of Centurions, undated
  - Honor Rolls, 1990-1992
  - The Campaign for Duke Booklet, 1990
  - The Campaign for Duke Newsletter, 1990-1991
  - A Community Pledged to Posterity, 1992
  - Brochures: Endowments, Scholarships and Funds, undated
  - Centers and Programs, undated
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1979-2003
- Gift Records/Endowment Funds, 1950-2001
  Series includes accessions A79-51, A93-57, A94-125, A96-4, A88-16, A95-69, A96-125, UA2011-0015 and materials with an unknown provenance.
  - Endowment Funds, 1964-1988 (Box 12)
    - Folder 1: A
    - Folder 2: B
    - Folder 3: C
    - Folder 4: D-F
    - Folder 5: G
    - Folder 6: H
    - Folder 7: I-L
    - Folder 8: Mc-M
    - Folder 9: N-S
    - Folder 10: T-Z
  - Annual Giving Loyalty Fund Report, 1950
  - C. S. Douglas Fund - "The Peacemaking Mentality" by Anna G. Douglas [Typescript], circa 1957
  - C. S. Douglas Fund -- "Field Study of Peacemaking in the U.N." by Anna Douglas, circa 1957?
  - C. S. Douglas Fund, 1984-1993 "In Honor of Those Who Enable Learning" Banquet Programs, 1979-1981
  - Plan of Acton Reports, Andrew D. Parker, 1982
  - Plan of Action Report, 1983
  - Washington Duke Club, 1980-1989
  - William Preston Few Association, 1983-circa 1989
  - William Preston Few Association and Washington Duke Club Gift Club Directory, 1986-1988
  - Annual Fund Calendar, 2000-2001
  - Office of Gift Records: Policy Manual, 1995
  - Memoranda, 1995
  - Reports: Three Year Comparative Report, 1994 RESTRICTED
  - Duke Views Screen Saver, 1996
  - Announcements, Invitations, etc., 1999
  - Duke Annual Fund Executive Committee, late 1970s-early 1980s (7 folders) (Box 28)
  - Duke Annual Fund Executive Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous/Oversize Materials
  Series includes accessions A84-49, A92-58, A94-109, A95-69, A2005-0001, A2002-12, A2005-0033, and UA2009-0010.
  - Printed Materials (Box 13)
    - The Chronicle, 1998 Oct. 5
    - The Campaign for Duke School of Engineering, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for Duke University Libraries, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for Duke University Medical Center, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for the Divinity School, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for Duke Chapel, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for the School of Law, circa 1998
    - The Campaign for Duke, circa 1998
  - Printed Material (Box 14)
    - Duke Campaign Thresholds, 1985-1991, copies 1-2
    - Campaign Report, 1990, 1990/1991
    - The Campaign for Duke: A Final Report, June 1992
  - Printed Material and Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - The Duke Honor Roll, 1991/1992, 1993/1994
    - Interview with Charles A. Dukes, 1967
    - Duke University Foundation Handbook for Faculty and Staff, 1971
    - Proposed Perkins Memorial Plaques, Ink Drawings
    - Hart Report, 1966
  - Gift Records/History of Funds, 1896-1971 (Box 16-23)
    - Volume 1 (Box 16)
    - Volume 2 (Box 17)
    - Volume 3 (Box 18)
    - Volume 4 (Box 19)
    - Volume 5 (Box 20)
    - Volume 6 (Box 21)
    - Volume 7 (Box 22)
    - Volume 8 (Box 23)
  - Scrapbook (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook (Box 25)
  - Volunteer Solicitor Training videocassette, undated (Box 26)
  - Duke Seminar Task Force Report, 1994
  - Final Report of the Task Force on Prospect Management and Regionalization, 1994
  - Task Force Recommendations, 1994
  - Hinkle, Marion, 1994
  - The Science Resource Initiative, undated
  - Time Capsule (non-circulating) (Box 27)
- Material Separated from Collection
  - Tape recording, J. A. Thomas, Jr. [Check with Archives Staff for location]
  - Architectural Drawings, 3 tubes [Drawing Storage]
  - Campaign for Duke Website [archival storage server]